<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lindemann</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lindemann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recognition and Observation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/notes/recognition-and-observation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/notes/recognition-and-observation/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago, in my little book of quotes, I connected two thoughts by Charles Péguy and Michel Foucault, both dedicated to observation:&#xA;You must always say what you see: but above all, and it is more difficult, you must always see what you see.&#xA;Charles Péguy (Radio France)&#xA;Curiosity is a vice that has been stigmatized by Christianity, philosophy, and even by a certain conception of science. Curiosity, frivolity. Yet, I like the word; it evokes care; it evokes the attention we give to what exists (&amp;hellip;) ; a certain determination to break free from our familiarities and to look at the same things differently (&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calendar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/cal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/cal/</guid>
      <description>I use Calendly to give secure access to my calendar.&#xA;Open https://calendly.com/mathieu_lindemann/ to access it and book a call.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Scary Judge of Talent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/notes/scary-judge-of-talent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/notes/scary-judge-of-talent/</guid>
      <description>I previously mentioned the importance I attach to observation1.&#xA;Among the domains where this quality seems particularly important to me, even indispensable, I place recruitment. Indeed, I pay very close attention to the elements I wish to observe during the hiring process and during the first few months after a new employee joins.&#xA;Perhaps one day I will deserve the Al Pacinesque title of &amp;ldquo;scary judge of talent.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Note on the importance of observation: here&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Science for Dogs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/notes/data-science-for-dogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/notes/data-science-for-dogs/</guid>
      <description>After a youth marked by a dubious taste for useless exactitudes, I believed that the engineering degree obtained at the peak of my intellectual glory almost 20 years ago would grant me enough humility and common sense to resist any scientific vanity until the end of my days. The sad reality is that a bag of dog food was enough to derail me.&#xA;Dog Food and Linear Regression It all started when our veterinarian informed us that my daughter&amp;rsquo;s puppy would weigh around 35kg as an adult.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Observation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/notes/observation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/notes/observation/</guid>
      <description>The sense of observation is rarely mentioned as a factor of success in our personal or professional lives.&#xA;The video below corrects this injustice in less than 90 seconds.&#xA;Published on LinkedIn1, this video is accompanied by comments praising various qualities of coach BriAnna Garza: her humility when she apologizes for not acting sooner, her pedagogical sense when she remains silent after a missed shot, or her enthusiasm when she shouts to the player that he is a true shooter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google: theory vs practice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/notes/google-theory-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/notes/google-theory-practice/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes meet founders unsure of their ability to scale their organization. One reason is that they compare their practices with what they think exists at Google or Facebook.&#xA;Since I started two companies myself1 and also managed teams at Google, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my two cents here.&#xA;Don&amp;rsquo;t try to apply inapplicable processes First, scaling your organization doesn&amp;rsquo;t require adopting methods published by Google, Netflix, or Amazon. These companies are facing problems and have ressources (human, financial and technological) that are irrelevant to most companies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspirations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/notes/inspirations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/notes/inspirations/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t expect this site to enlighten you with timeless and dazzling knowledge that its author, speaking of himself in the third person because it sounds nice, would have acquired over the course of their rich and remarkable life.&#xA;On the contrary, most of the guiding compasses used by the aforementioned author were originally expressed by others, either orally or in writing, and are so publicly available that they are listed below.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/guide/</guid>
      <description>This page tries to describe how I operate, to facilitate interactions at work or outside.&#xA;Bio My background is described here.&#xA;Biases Action: I prefer action over inaction. However, I also believe in thoughtful planning and anticipation as essential actions. If you find me rushing too quickly, please feel free to provide patient guidance. Communication Intensity: I value more communication over less. If you ever feel overwhelmed by my messages, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to let me know, and I&amp;rsquo;ll reciprocate the feedback if needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 21:59:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/about/</guid>
      <description>Who I am a husband and father of two.&#xA;I am an engineer, entrepreneur and computer scientist.&#xA;I was born in France in the early 1980’s.&#xA;Where I live in Lausanne, Switzerland.&#xA;I also lived and worked in France, in Vietnam, in Malaysia and in the U.S.&#xA;I have been working remotely or with distributed teams for 15+ years.&#xA;What When I am not busy teaching my kids how to use a glue gun, I manage tech organizations, mostly building or turning them around.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calendar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cal/</guid>
      <description>I use Calendly to give secure access to my calendar.&#xA;Open https://calendly.com/mathieu_lindemann/ to access it and book a call.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/cv/</guid>
      <description>Click here to go to my LinkedIn profile page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cv/</guid>
      <description>Click here to go to my LinkedIn profile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/home/</guid>
      <description>This site lets you read short posts about:&#xA;Who I am: here Subjects that draw my attention: there ML</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quotes • Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/quotes/all/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/quotes/all/</guid>
      <description>Collecting quotes is one of my guilty pleasures.&#xA;The only criterion for a sentence to find its place in the list below is to make me think. The bar to pass is usually quite low.&#xA;Once in the list, a quote remains even if I later find it superficial, stupid or offending.&#xA;Consequently, the following criteria were not taken into account:&#xA;Whether or not I agree with what is said 1.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
