<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Lindemann.co</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Lindemann.co</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recognition and Observation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/recognition-and-observation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/recognition-and-observation/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago, in my little book of quotes, I connected two thoughts by Charles Péguy and Michel Foucault, both dedicated to observation:&#xA;You must always say what you see: but above all, and it is more difficult, you must always see what you see.&#xA;Charles Péguy (Radio France)&#xA;Curiosity is a vice that has been stigmatized by Christianity, philosophy, and even by a certain conception of science. Curiosity, frivolity. Yet, I like the word; it evokes care; it evokes the attention we give to what exists (&amp;hellip;) ; a certain determination to break free from our familiarities and to look at the same things differently (&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Scary Judge of Talent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/scary-judge-of-talent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/scary-judge-of-talent/</guid>
      <description>I previously mentioned the importance I attach to observation1.&#xA;Among the domains where this quality seems particularly important to me, even indispensable, I place recruitment. Indeed, I pay very close attention to the elements I wish to observe during the hiring process and during the first few months after a new employee joins.&#xA;Perhaps one day I will deserve the Al Pacinesque title of &amp;ldquo;scary judge of talent.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Note on the importance of observation: here&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Observation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/observation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/observation/</guid>
      <description>The sense of observation is rarely mentioned as a factor of success in our personal or professional lives.&#xA;The video below corrects this injustice in less than 90 seconds.&#xA;Published on LinkedIn1, this video is accompanied by comments praising various qualities of coach BriAnna Garza: her humility when she apologizes for not acting sooner, her pedagogical sense when she remains silent after a missed shot, or her enthusiasm when she shouts to the player that he is a true shooter.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
